{
  "JKSSB": {
    "Finance Accounts Assistant": {
      "Test Paper 1": {
        "gk": [
          {
            "question": "The bill for the Jammu and Kashmir Reorganisation Act, 2019 was introduced in Rajya Sabha by:",
            "options": [
              "Amit Shah",
              "G. Kishan Reddy",
              "Rajnath Singh",
              "Ravi Shankar Prasad"
            ],
            "answer": "Amit Shah"
          },
          {
            "question": "The Subar Dhar Mela takes place in which of the following locations of Jammu and Kashmir?",
            "options": ["Bhaderwah", "Kishtwar", "Srinagar", "Doda"],
            "answer": "Bhaderwah"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which is the only active volcanic island in India?",
            "options": [
              "Minicoy Island",
              "Amindivi Island",
              "Barren Island",
              "Laccadive Island"
            ],
            "answer": "Barren Island"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which among the following is the largest wetland sanctuary in the state of Gujarat and one of the biggest in India?",
            "options": [
              "Kaziranga national park",
              "Nalsarovar Bird Sanctuary",
              "Sultanpur Bird Sanctuary",
              "Uppalapadu Bird Sanctuary"
            ],
            "answer": "Nalsarovar Bird Sanctuary"
          },
          {
            "question": "In which of the following states of India is the Dree festival celebrated?",
            "options": ["Manipur", "Assam", "Arunachal Pradesh", "Nagaland"],
            "answer": "Arunachal Pradesh"
          },
          {
            "question": "During which season are walnuts harvested in Jammu and Kashmir?",
            "options": ["Winter", "Summer", "Autumn", "Monsoon"],
            "answer": "Autumn"
          },
          {
            "question": "Operation Sadbhavana is an unique humane initiative undertaken in Jammu and Kashmir to help people affected by terrorism and is launched by the:",
            "options": [
              "Indian Army",
              "Central Government of India",
              "Home Department, Government of Jammu & Kashmir",
              "District Development Councils"
            ],
            "answer": "Indian Army"
          },
          {
            "question": "The Vale of Kashmir (Kashmir valley) is the sole producer of which product (in India)?",
            "options": ["Sapphire", "Walnut", "Saffron", "Peach"],
            "answer": "Saffron"
          },
          {
            "question": "As per census 2011, with regards to sex ratio, the number of females per 1000 males in India was:",
            "options": ["890", "1140", "990", "940"],
            "answer": "940"
          },
          {
            "question": "Read the following statements and choose the CORRECT option. Statement I: Wheat and Barley are grown as rabi crops in India. Statement II: Rabi crops are sown in the beginning of the monsoon season and harvested between October and December.",
            "options": [
              "Statement I: FALSE, Statement II: TRUE",
              "Statement I: TRUE, Statement II: FALSE",
              "Statement I: FALSE, Statement II: FALSE",
              "Statement I: TRUE, Statement II: TRUE"
            ],
            "answer": "Statement I: TRUE, Statement II: FALSE"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which among the following lakes is located in Jammu and Kashmir?",
            "options": [
              "Sambhar lake",
              "Lonar lake",
              "Agara lake",
              "Wular lake"
            ],
            "answer": "Wular lake"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which country shares boundary with Pakistan in the West?",
            "options": ["Iran", "India", "Iraq", "China"],
            "answer": "Iran"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which of the following soils is suitable for saffron cultivation in Jammu and Kashmir region?",
            "options": [
              "Gruti soil",
              "Karewa soil",
              "Nambal soil",
              "Tand soil"
            ],
            "answer": "Karewa soil"
          },
          {
            "question": "The origin of which of the following lakes in Jammu and Kashmir is associated with the Mahabharata?",
            "options": [
              "Dal lake",
              "Surinsar lake",
              "Nagin lake",
              "Wullar lake"
            ],
            "answer": "Surinsar lake"
          },
          {
            "question": "Gulab Singh was eventually made the Raja of Jammu through which the following Treaties dated: 16-3-1846?",
            "options": [
              "Treaty of Delhi",
              "Treaty of Lahore",
              "Treaty of Amritsar",
              "Treaty of Srinagar"
            ],
            "answer": "Treaty of Amritsar"
          },
          {
            "question": "In 2021, the Jammu and Kashmir Government filed an application to seek GI tag for which of the following species of mushrooms?",
            "options": ["Telia Sattar", "Gucchi", "Boda", "Matij"],
            "answer": "Gucchi"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which among the following destinations is the base camp of the Amarnath Yatra?",
            "options": ["Sonmarg", "Gulmarg", "Pampore", "Sanasar"],
            "answer": "Sonmarg"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which among the following was the residential palace of Raja Amar Singh, located in Jammu?",
            "options": ["Bahu Fort", "Amar Mahal", "Akhnoor Fort", "Gol Ghar"],
            "answer": "Amar Mahal"
          },
          {
            "question": "The Jawaharlal Nehru Port Trust (JNPT) is the premier container handling port in India, accounting for around 50% of the total containerized cargo volume, across the major ports of India. It is located in:",
            "options": ["Navi Mumbai", "Kochi", "Visakhapatnam", "Chennai"],
            "answer": "Navi Mumbai"
          },
          {
            "question": "In October 2021, Government of India signed a share purchase agreement with Tata Sons for sale of which of the following airlines for Rs 18,000 crores?",
            "options": ["IndiGo", "SpiceJet", "Go First", "Air India"],
            "answer": "Air India"
          },
          {
            "question": "When did the Indigo revolt in Bengal, a peasant movement, start?",
            "options": ["1837", "1859", "1871", "1889"],
            "answer": "1859"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which of the following countries lies to the south of India?",
            "options": ["Pakistan", "Maldives", "Myanmar", "Bangladesh"],
            "answer": "Maldives"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which of the following forts of Jammu and Kashmir is also known as the Koh-e-Maran?",
            "options": [
              "Chitkan Fort",
              "Akhnoor Fort",
              "Hari Parbat Fort",
              "Bahu Fort"
            ],
            "answer": "Hari Parbat Fort"
          },
          {
            "question": "As per Census 2011, what is the literacy rate of India?",
            "options": ["67.02 %", "70.10 %", "74.04 %", "81.03 %"],
            "answer": "74.04 %"
          },
          {
            "question": "In 2021, under the Pradhan Mantri Kaushal Vikas Yojana, a pilot project was launched to revive which of the following crafts of Jammu and Kashmir?",
            "options": ["Calico Painting", "Basohli", "Phool Kari", "Namda"],
            "answer": "Namda"
          },
          {
            "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE with reference to the Jammu and Kashmir Reorganization Act of 2019?",
            "options": [
              "Ladakh has been formulated into a separate Union territory without a Legislative Assembly",
              "Jammu and Kashmir has become a Union Territory with a Legislative Assembly",
              "Governor of existing State of Jammu and Kashmir to be common Lieutenant Governor",
              "There will be no reservation for Scheduled Tribe and Scheduled Caste in Jammu and Kashmir"
            ],
            "answer": "There will be no reservation for Scheduled Tribe and Scheduled Caste in Jammu and Kashmir"
          }
        ],
        "accountancy": [
          {
            "question": "The assets that can be easily converted into cash within a short period i.e., 1 year or less is known as?",
            "options": [
              "Current Assets",
              "Fixed assets",
              "Intangible assets",
              "Investments"
            ],
            "answer": "Current Assets"
          }
        ],
        "maths": [
          {
            "question": "The word processing feature that catches most random typographical errors and misspellings is known as?",
            "options": [
              "Grammar Checker",
              "Spell Checker",
              "Word Checker",
              "None of the these"
            ],
            "answer": "Spell Checker"
          }
        ],
        "statistics": [
          {
            "question": "The word processing feature that catches most random typographical errors and misspellings is known as?",
            "options": [
              "Grammar Checker",
              "Spell Checker",
              "Word Checker",
              "None of the these"
            ],
            "answer": "Spell Checker"
          }
        ],
        "science": [
          {
            "question": "The word processing feature that catches most random typographical errors and misspellings is known as?",
            "options": [
              "Grammar Checker",
              "Spell Checker",
              "Word Checker",
              "None of the these"
            ],
            "answer": "Spell Checker"
          }
        ],
        "english": [
          {
            "question": "The word processing feature that catches most random typographical errors and misspellings is known as?",
            "options": [
              "Grammar Checker",
              "Spell Checker",
              "Word Checker",
              "None of the these"
            ],
            "answer": "Spell Checker"
          }
        ],
        "computer": [
          {
            "question": "The word processing feature that catches most random typographical errors and misspellings is known as?",
            "options": [
              "Grammar Checker",
              "Spell Checker",
              "Word Checker",
              "None of the these"
            ],
            "answer": "Spell Checker"
          },
          {
            "question": "First time when the operating system is loading into main memory and peripheral devices are checked called?",
            "options": [
              "Freeze booting",
              "Hot booting",
              "Warm booting",
              "Cold booting"
            ],
            "answer": "Cold booting"
          },
          {
            "question": "The memory resident portion of the operating system is called?",
            "options": ["API", "CMOS", "Register", "Kernel"],
            "answer": "Kernel"
          }
        ],
        "economics": [
          {
            "question": "The word processing feature that catches most random typographical errors and misspellings is known as?",
            "options": [
              "Grammar Checker",
              "Spell Checker",
              "Word Checker",
              "None of the these"
            ],
            "answer": "Spell Checker"
          }
        ]
      },
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Stock Assistant": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Junior Assistant": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Supervisior": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Panchayat Accounts Assistant": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    }
  },
  "JKPSC": {
    "Programmer": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Kashmir Administrative Service": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Assistant Registrar Cooperative Societies": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    }
  },
  "Kashmir University": {
    "Junior Assistant": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Assistant Professor": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Network Executive": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    }
  },
  "UGC NET": {
    "Computer Science": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "English": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Urdu": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    }
  },

  "SKIMS": {
    "Lab Assistant": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Junior Assistant": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Radiologist": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    }
  },
  "SKUAST": {
    "Junior Assistant": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Lab Assistant": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    },
    "Network Executive": {
      "Test Paper 1": {},
      "Test Paper 2": {},
      "Test Paper 3": {},
      "Test Paper 4": {}
    }
  }
}
